Hadi Lashkari Ghouchani

Software Engineer

@ hadi.pro.dev@gmail.com

+34 645869103

Parcelona, Spain

github.com/hadilq

M medium.com/@hadilq.dev

in linkedin.com/in/hadilq

Summary

A curious developer with over 16 years of experience in software development, where almost 6 years of his experience covers Android development, over 2 years covers teaching algorithms and programming in universities, and over 8 years covers academic and self-employed experiences while he was a student. An Introvert person who has profound learning and contributing skills. A creative, value driven and passionate

developer who enjoys doing math, solving problems and creating scalable, maintainable, testable and efficient apps to make the world a better place to live.

A person whose goal is to surround himself with happy, creative, motivative and clever persons, so his talent becomes flourished

He's interested in Data Science, Machine Learning, Functional Programming, Differentiable Programming, Category Theory, Math, etc. so constantly looking forward to learning related technologies to use in Mobile apps.

Experience

Staff Android Developer

at iFood

Barcelona, Spain

iFood is an ambitious project to build an entire food delivery ecosystem for all around the world. Currently, it's the biggest food delivery in Brazil, Colombia and Mexico, with 50+ million apps installed on Android devices alone. The Android project is highly modularized to make it possible for 50+ develpers working on it fast.

- · Propose and implement composite build to handle dependency management in Gradle. It decreased the rebuild time while updating a library from more than 13 min to less than a minute
- Implement Android side of metadata project. Its purpose is gathering all information of our highly modularized Android/iOS projects in a dashboard along backend information.
- Propose and apply a concept to move away the legacy code from the root module to another one. It decreased the rebuild time of freed up modules by 55%
- Wrap up external libraries to better handling panic situations.

Technologies:

- Dagger 2, Room, Kotlin Coroutines, Moshi, WorkManager / Mockk, Robolectric, jUnit, etc.
- Agile, Sprint, Github Flow, CI/CD, Gradle Enterprise
- Atlassian Jira, Atlassian Confluence, Github, Jenkins, Slack, Databricks, Firebase, Bugsnag, Logzio, etc.

Senior Android Developer

at Letgo

m Oct. 2019 - Mar. 2021

Barcelona, Spain

Letgo is the biggest classified marketplace in Turkey with 15+ million apps installed on Android devices

- Improve the performance of loading feeds by at least a minute
- · Fix multiple Memory leaks
- Known as "The man who broke the escape room" to emphasize his ability to think out of the box

- Dagger 2, RxJava 2, Room / Mockito, Espresso, Robolectric, Jacoco, Ktlint, Fastlane, etc.
- · Agile, Sprint, Github Flow, CI/CD, Dynamic Feature Module Delivery
- Atlassian Jira, Atlassian Confluence, Github, Jenkins, Slack, Figma, New Relic, Firebase, Amplitude, etc.

Lead Android Developer

at Sheypoor

🛗 Jan. 2018 - Jan. 2019

O Tehran, Iran

Sheypoor is one of two lead classified marketplaces in Iran with 1.5+ million users per day, 13+ million overall users and 344+ million sessions.

• Increase the number of users per day from 0.5+ million to 1.5+ million in a year.

- Dagger 2, RxJava 2, Butter Knife, Greendao / Mockito, Espresso, Jacoco, etc.
- Agile, Kanban, Git Flow, CI/CD / Pivotal Tracker, Github, Jenkins, Slack, Zeplin, etc.

Senior Android Developer

at Myket

Tehran, Iran

Myket is one of two lead app stores in Iran with over 8+ million users

• Starting TDD and installing Jenking's pipeline to handle CI/CD.

Java and C# developer

at Soha System

m Mar. 2015 - Aug. 2015

O Tehran, Iran

SOHA is formed to focus on solutions based on smart cards.

· Implementing Android and desktop apps.

Lecturer

m Feb. 2012 - Dec. 2014

Mashhad, Iran

After two years of enrollment by conscription, he had been starting his work in two universities, Payame Noor University and Sadjad University of Technology.

Courses Taught:

· Application of Computers in Physics, Mathematical Physics, etc

Article / Repository

 M 2021 iFood Engneering post: Modularization tip: optimize the Root Module.

 M 2021 ProAndroidDev post: Happy Railway As increased.

2021 ProAndroidDev post: Happy Railway. An improvement for Railway Oriented Programming in Kotlin. 2021 Library: Happy is a library to auto-generate Kotlin code to make calling APIs more concise.

2020 POC: Rust Flutter Reactive is an idea to use Flutter as UI and Rust for the main project.

↑ 2020 Make Log4k Multiplatform: Simple logging library for Android, iOS, Mac, etc.

1 2020 ProAndroidDev post: A/B Testing Myths

2020 Sample App: Provide a full implementation for a No-Framework Dependency Injection in Kotlin

↑ 2020 Contributing on Arrow Library: Arrow is a library for Typed Functional Programming in Kotlin
↑ 2020 Library: A Kotlin compiler plugin that generates trackable method
↑ 2020 Medium post: Save State By Using RxJava or Kotlin Flow
↑ 2020 Medium post: RxJava instead of LiveData in MVVM

M 2020 Medium post: RxJava instead of LiveData in MVVM ↑ 2020 Library: A glue between the lifecycle of LifecycleOwner in Android and upstreams in RxJava

🔿 2020 Library: A glue between the lifecycle of LifecycleOwner in Android and Kotlin Coroutines

 ☼ 2020 Library: Simplifier for unnecessary complex lifecycles
 ☼ 2019 Sample App: Functional Programming + Clean Architecture 2019 Sample App: Movie Challenge

റ്റ് 2019 Math Library: Modularized, mathematical and multiplatform Kotlin library 🚺 2018 ProAndroidDev post: Logging in Kotlin

O 2018 Log4k Library: Easy logging library, but unfortunately it's in Sheypoor repository
 M 2018 ProAndroidDev post: Reactive MVVM architectural pattern

2018 Sample App: Clean Architecture + RMVVM

▼ 2018 ProAndroidDev post: Loading entities from database and server API by using RxJava

2018 ProAndroidDev post: LiveData with single events 2018 LiveEvent library: It's useful to propagate single event to View

Education

Sharif University Of Technology Payame Noor University

M.Sc in Physics

in Physics

₩ Feb. 2010 O Tehran, Iran Mashhad, Iran

Tools / Skills

Android

Lifecycles/LiveData/Navigation/Paging/ViewModel Multidex/Test/Data Binding/WorkManager/Room Android Architecture Components/JetPack Dagger 2/RxJava 2/Retrofit 2/... Kotlin Multiplatform/Kotlin Coroutines Kotlin Compiler Plugin/. Compose/Data Binding/View Binding/...

Architecture

Clean Architecture/Hexagonal Architecture Unidirectional data flow Architecture MVVM/MVI/MVP/RMVVM

Principle

Clean Code/SOLID **Object Oriented Programming** Functional Programming Stable Dependencies Principle Stable Abstractions Principle

Design Pattern

Factory/Builder/Singleton/... Adapter/Facade/Proxy/Visitor/Delegate/... Strategy/Chain of responsibility/...

Android test library

JUnit/Mockito/Espresso/Jacoco/...

Build Tool

Gradle/Cargo/Sbt/Maven/Ant/Make/...

Command Line Tool

grep/sed/netstat/awk/docker/... adb/sdkmanager/avdmanager/...

Development Tool

Pivotal Tracker/Jira/Jenkins/Travis/CircleCi/...

Programing Language

Java/Kotlin/Rust/Scala/Haskell/Python Groovy/Dart/Javascript/Ruby..

Operating System

Linux(Nix OS/Fedora/Ubuntu/Debian), OS X

Special Honor

- 2020 Had an offer from MobileLIVE, Toronto, Canada
- 2020 Had an offer from iFood, Remote 2019 Had an offer from Kik, Kitechener, Canada
- 2019 Had an offer from Letgo, Barcelona, Spain 2019 Had an offer from CRITICAL Techworks, BMW,
- Porto, Portugal - 2019 Had an offer from The Next Big Thing, Berlin, Ger-
- many 2018 Received result-oriented badge in Sheypoor
- 2007 Ranked 44th among more than five thousand participants in the National Graduate Entrance Exam in

Language

English: Advance Farsi: Native

The source of this resume is in github